export const data = [
    {
        "id" : 1,
        "prompt" : "Which of the following anti-hypertensive is correctly matched to its class?",
        "choices": [
            "Aliskiren - vasodilator",
            "Captopril - angiotensin II receptor 1 blocker",
            "Clonidine - α1 blocker", 
            "Diltiazem - Ca\u00b2\u207a channel inhibitor",
            "Hydralazine - renin inhibitor",
            "Losartan - angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitor",
            "Terazosin - α2 agonist"],
        "correct": "Diltiazem - Ca\u00b2\u207a channel inhibitor",
        "tags":["PD","easy","MoA","SNS","Cardiology"]
    },
    {
        "id" : 2,
        "prompt" : "A 63 y/o patient with a history of dyslipidemia and hypertension presents to the cardiology clinic. Through a special technique it is found that the endothelial layer of his right brachial artery is severely damaged, but the vascular smooth muscle is intact. Assuming you can locally inject vasodilators like acetylcholine and histamine, predict the resulting vasodilatory response and why?",
        "choices": [
            "Decreased vasodilatory response to both vasodilators due to decreased nitric oxide mediated smooth muscle relaxation",
            "Decreased vasodilatory response to both vasodilators due to the increased patency from the loss of the endothelium layer",
            "Increased vasodilatory response to acetylcholine only due to direct activity on vascular smooth muscle to increase in nitric oxide production", 
            "Normal vasodilatory response to both vasodilators due to direct increase in nitric oxide production in vascular smooth muscle"],
        "correct": "Decreased vasodilatory response to both vasodilators due to decreased nitric oxide mediated smooth muscle relaxation",
        "tags":["PD","medium","Cardiology"]
    },
   {
        "id" : 3,
        "prompt" : "A 42 y/o patient who just underwent a gender affirming surgery (male transitioning to female) is diagnosed with hypertension. On her medication list is spironolactone and estrogen. Which of the following medications would you prescribe for her hypertension?",
        "choices": [
            "Amlodipine",
            "Captopril",
            "Hydrochlorothiazide", 
            "Losartan"],
        "correct": "Hydrochlorothiazide",
        "tags":["PD","MoA","hard","Cardiology","Nephrology","side effects","Endocrinology"]
    },  
    {
        "id" : 4,
        "prompt" : "Which of the following is NOT an effect of antihypertensives that target the RAAS?",
        "choices": [
            "Decrease cardiac contractility",
            "Decrease sympathetic nerve activity",
            "Inhibit aldosterone secretion", 
            "Inhibit Na\u207a reabsorption",
            "Inhibit vasoconstriction"],
        "correct": "Decrease cardiac contractility",
        "tags":["PD","medium","MoA","Cardiology"]
    },
  {
        "id" : 5,
        "prompt" : "A 56 y/o patient recently diagnosed with HTN presents to the clinic with a dry cough and angioedema. He was recently put on a new medication for his hypertension. What is the identity of the drug and what drug that works in the same system would you switch him to?",
        "choices": [
            "Captopril. Switch to losartan",
            "Captopril. Switch to metoprolol",
            "Losartan. Switch to captopril", 
            "Losartan. Switch to metoprolol"],
        "correct": "Captopril. Switch to losartan",
        "tags":["PD","easy","side effects","Cardiology"]
    },
{
        "id" : 6,
        "prompt" : "Which of the following is a legitimate difference between ramipril and valsartan?",
        "choices": [
            "Ramipril has a vasodilatory effect due to decreased bradykinin breakdown",
            "Ramipril is a renin inhibitor, while valsartan is an angiotensin receptor 1 blocker",
            "Ramipril is an ACE inhibitor, while valsartan is an angiotensin receptor 2 blocker", 
            "Valsartan is contraindicated in asthma, while ramipril is contraindicated in renal artery stenosis",
            "Valsartan has a vasodilatory effect due to decreased bradykinin breakdown"],
        "correct": "Ramipril has a vasodilatory effect due to decreased bradykinin breakdown",
        "tags":["PD","easy","MoA","Cardiology"]
    }, 
{
        "id" : 7,
        "prompt" : "A 50 y/o patient with type 2 diabetes mellitus and hypertension presents to the nephrology clinic after a recent diagnosis of diabetic nephropathy (progressive damage to the kidneys due to high blood pressure and hyperglycemia). The nephrologist suggests that the patient’s medication should be switched from amlodipine to an ACE inhibitor (ACEi) to help slow down the progression of his kidney disease. Is this an appropriate intervention, why or why not?",
        "choices": [
            "No, ACEi are contraindicated in any renal disease",
            "No, ACEi are not as efficacious as amlodipine in treating hypertension, thus more blood pressure mediated damage to the kidneys will occur",
            "Yes, ACEi will lead to efferent arteriole vasodilation, which will reduce intraglomerular pressure and hyperfiltration (decrease GFR), thus protecting the glomerulus", 
            "Yes, ACEi are more efficacious than amlodipine in treating hypertension, thus less blood pressure mediated damage to the kidneys will occur"],
        "correct": "Yes, ACEi will lead to efferent arteriole vasodilation, which will reduce intraglomerular pressure and hyperfiltration (decrease GFR), thus protecting the glomerulus",
        "tags":["PD","hard","MoA","Cardiology","Nephrology","Endocrinology","Diabetes"]
    }, 
{
        "id" : 8,
        "prompt" : "What differentiates the mechanism of actions of amlodipine, verapamil, and diltiazem?",
        "choices": [
            "Amlodipine blocks cardiac and vascular Ca\u00b2\u207a channels, while verapamil and diltiazem primarily block vascular Ca\u00b2\u207a channels",
            "Amlodipine primarily blocks vascular Ca\u00b2\u207a channels, while verapamil and diltiazem block cardiac and vascular Ca\u00b2\u207a channels",
            "Dilitazem blocks cardiac and vascular Ca\u00b2\u207a channels, while verapamil and amlodipine primarily block vascular Ca\u00b2\u207a channels", 
            "Verapamil blocks cardiac and vascular Ca\u00b2\u207a channels, while amlodipine and diltiazem primarily block vascular Ca\u00b2\u207a channels",
            "Verapamil primarily blocks vascular Ca\u00b2\u207a channels, while amlodipine and diltiazem block cardiac and vascular Ca\u00b2\u207a channels"],
        "correct": "Amlodipine primarily blocks vascular Ca\u00b2\u207a channels, while verapamil and diltiazem block cardiac and vascular Ca\u00b2\u207a channels",
        "tags":["PD","medium","MoA","Cardiology"]
    },
{
        "id" : 9,
        "prompt" : "A 72 y/o patient with hypertension, asthma, and idiopathic bradycardia presents to the clinic to change his HTN medication. He has had trouble tolerating the side effects of ACEi, ARB, diuretics, and both classes of CCB. The only class left are the β-blockers, but your preceptor is apprehensive in prescribing one given his comorbidities. Using your knowledge of pharmacodynamics you would suggest which β-blocker?",
        "choices": [
            "Acebutolol",
            "Atenolol",
            "Carvedilol", 
            "Metoprolol",
            "Propranolol"],
        "correct": "Acebutolol",
        "tags":["PD","medium","MoA","Cardiology","side effects"]
    },
{
        "id" : 10,
        "prompt" : "Which of the following drugs would you expect to have reflex tachycardia?",
        "choices": [
            "Clonidine",
            "Hydralazine",
            "Labetalol", 
            "Propranolol",
            "C and D"],
        "correct": "Hydralazine",
        "tags":["PD","medium","MoA","Cardiology","side effects"]
    },   
{
        "id" : 11,
        "prompt" : "A 73 y/o patient with well controlled hypertension forgets to take his hypertension medication for a few days. Suddenly his blood pressure skyrockets and he is seen in the ER, where he is observed and treated before being discharged. Which of the following is most likely the anti-hypertensive medication that he stopped taking?",
        "choices": [
            "Aliskiren",
            "Captopril",
            "Carvedilol", 
            "Hydralazine",
            "Losartan"],
        "correct": "Carvedilol",
        "tags":["PD","medium","MoA","Cardiology","side effects"]
    },   
{
        "id" : 12,
        "prompt" : "A 32 y/o pregnant patient G3T1P1 presents to the ER with a severe headache, blurred vision, retrosternal pain, and confusion. Some vitals are BP 184/120, T 37.3 \u00b0C, HR 95, RR 25. A urine dipstick for protein is performed and it comes back positive for proteinuria. Being an astute medical student, you recognize the presentation as preeclampsia. Which of the following drugs could you use to lower the patient’s blood pressure?",
        "choices": [
            "Captopril",
            "Furosemide",
            "Labetalol", 
            "Losartan",
            "Nifedipine",
            "C and E"],
        "correct": "C and E",
        "tags":["PD","hard","Cardiology","side effects","Ob/Gyn"]
    },
{
        "id" : 13,
        "prompt" : "How does prazosin cause orthostatic hypotension (OH)?",
        "choices": [
            "Activating α2 adrenergic receptor decreases SNS outflow, which prevents the reflexive increase in HR and peripheral vasoconstriction to overcome OH",
            "Activating α2 adrenergic receptor inhibits vaso and venoconstriction causing reduced venous return, cardiac output, and peripheral vasoconstriction to overcome OH",
            "Inhibiting α1 adrenergic receptor decreases SNS outflow, which prevents the reflexive increase in HR and peripheral vasoconstriction to overcome OH", 
            "Inhibiting α1 adrenergic receptor  inhibits vaso and venoconstriction causing reduced venous return, cardiac output, and peripheral vasoconstriction to overcome OH"],
        "correct": "Inhibiting α1 adrenergic receptor  inhibits vaso and venoconstriction causing reduced venous return, cardiac output, and peripheral vasoconstriction to overcome OH",
        "tags":["PD","medium","MoA","Cardiology","side effects","SNS"]
    },         
]